<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSpy v2020 (x64) (http://www.altova.com) by Andrew Auseon (Private) -->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_PYRAMIDS</zType>
		<Translation><![CDATA[The Great Pyramid of Giza is the oldest and largest of the three pyramids in the Giza pyramid complex bordering present-day Giza in Greater Cairo, Egypt. It is the oldest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, and the only one to remain largely intact.<br>
Egyptologists believe the pyramid was built as a tomb for the Fourth Dynasty Egyptian pharaoh Cheops and was constructed over a 20-year period.<br>Cheops's vizier, Hemiunu, is believed by some to be the architect of the Great Pyramid. It is thought that, at construction, the Great Pyramid was originally 147 metres (481 ft) tall.<br>The lengths of the sides at the base are difficult to reconstruct, given the absence of the casing, but recent analyses put them in a range of 230 metres (755 ft).]]>
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_GREAT_ZIGGURAT</zType>
		<Translation><![CDATA[The Great Ziggura of Ur, meaning "temple whose foundation creates aura" was built by King Ur-Nammu, who dedicated it in honour of Nanna/Sîn in approximately the 21st century BCE during the Third Dynasty of Ur. The massive step pyramid measured 64 m (210 ft) in length, 45 m (148 ft) in width and over 30 m (98 ft) in height. The height is speculative, as only the foundations of the Sumerian ziggurat have survived.<br>
The ziggurat was a piece in a temple complex that served as an administrative center for the city, and which was a shrine of the moon god Nanna, the patron deity of Ur.<br>The construction of the ziggurat was finished in the 21st century BCE by King Shulgi, who, in order to win the allegiance of cities, proclaimed himself a god.]]>
		
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ORACLE</zType>
		<Translation><![CDATA[The Pythia was the name of the high priestess of the Temple of Apollo at Delphi who also served as the oracle, also known as the Oracle of Delphi.<br>
The Pythia was established at the latest in the 8th century BC and was widely credited for her prophecies inspired by being filled by the spirit of the god (or enthusiasmos), in this case Apollo.<br>The Pythian priestess emerged pre-eminent by the end of 7th century BC and would continue to be consulted until the 4th century AD. During this period the Delphic Oracle was the most prestigious and authoritative oracle among the Greeks, and she was without a doubt the most powerful woman of the classical world. The oracle is one of the best-documented religious institutions of the classical Greeks.]]>
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_HANGING_GARDENS</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Hanging Gardens will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_NECROPOLIS</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Necropolis will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ISHTAR_GATE</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Ishtar Gate will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_LIGHTHOUSE</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Lighthouse will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_APADANA</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Apadana will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_MAUSOLEUM</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Mausoleum will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ACROPOLIS</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Acropolis will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_COLOSSUS</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Colosseus will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_MUSAEUM</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Musaeum will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_CIRCUS_MAXIMUS</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Circus Maximus will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_PANTHEON</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Pantheon will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_HAGIA_SOPHIA</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

Hagia Sophia will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_GRAND_BAZAAR</zType>
		<Translation>It is done...

The Grand Bazaar will stand as a testament to our people for all time, a symbol of our accomplishments today and of the glories yet to come.
</Translation>
	</Entry>
</Root>
