<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSpy v2020 (x64) (http://www.altova.com) by Andrew Auseon (Private) -->
<Root>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_PYRAMIDS</zType>
		<en-US>The Great Pyramid of Giza is the oldest and largest of the three pyramids in the Giza pyramid complex bordering present-day Giza in Greater Cairo, Egypt. It is the oldest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, and the only one to remain largely intact. 
Egyptologists believe the pyramid was built as a tomb for the Fourth Dynasty Egyptian pharaoh Cheops and was constructed over a 20-year period. Cheops's vizier, Hemiunu, is believed by some to be the architect of the Great Pyramid. It is thought that, at construction, the Great Pyramid was originally 147 metres (481 ft) tall. The lengths of the sides at the base are difficult to reconstruct, given the absence of the casing, but recent analyses put them in a range of 230 metres (755 ft).
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_GREAT_ZIGGURAT</zType>
		<en-US>The Great Ziggura of Ur, meaning "temple whose foundation creates aura" was built by King Ur-Nammu, who dedicated it in honour of Nanna/Sîn in approximately the 21st century BCE during the Third Dynasty of Ur. The massive step pyramid measured 64 m (210 ft) in length, 45 m (148 ft) in width and over 30 m (98 ft) in height. The height is speculative, as only the foundations of the Sumerian ziggurat have survived. 
The ziggurat was a piece in a temple complex that served as an administrative center for the city, and which was a shrine of the moon god Nanna, the patron deity of Ur. The construction of the ziggurat was finished in the 21st century BCE by King Shulgi, who, in order to win the allegiance of cities, proclaimed himself a god.
		
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ORACLE</zType>
		<en-US>The Pythia was the name of the high priestess of the Temple of Apollo at Delphi who also served as the oracle, also known as the Oracle of Delphi. 
The Pythia was established at the latest in the 8th century BC and was widely credited for her prophecies inspired by being filled by the spirit of the god (or enthusiasmos), in this case Apollo. The Pythian priestess emerged pre-eminent by the end of 7th century BC and would continue to be consulted until the 4th century AD. During this period the Delphic Oracle was the most prestigious and authoritative oracle among the Greeks, and she was without a doubt the most powerful woman of the classical world. The oracle is one of the best-documented religious institutions of the classical Greeks.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_HANGING_GARDENS</zType>
		<en-US>The Hanging Gardens of Babylon were one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World as listed by Hellenic culture. It was described as a remarkable feat of engineering with an ascending series of tiered gardens containing a wide variety of trees, shrubs, and vines, resembling a large green mountain constructed of mud bricks. 
According to one legend, the Hanging Gardens were built alongside a grand palace known as The Marvel of Mankind, by the Neo-Babylonian King Nebuchadnezzar II (who ruled between 605 and 562 BC), for his Median wife Queen Amytis, because she missed the green hills and valleys of her homeland. 
Its the only one of the Seven Wonders for which the location has not been definitively established. There are no extant Babylonian texts that mention the gardens, and no definitive archaeological evidence has been found in Babylon.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_NECROPOLIS</zType>
		<en-US>The Giza Necropolis of ancient Egypt is one of the oldest and probably the most well-known necropolis in the world since the Great Pyramid of Giza was included in the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. 
Aside from the pyramids, which were reserved for the burial of Pharaohs, the Egyptian necropoleis included mastabas, a typical royal tomb of the early Dynastic period.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ISHTAR_GATE</zType>
		<en-US>The Ishtar Gate was the eighth gate to the inner city of Babylon. It was constructed in about 575 BCE by order of King Nebuchadnezzar II on the north side of the city. 
It was part of a grand walled processional way leading into the city. The walls were finished in glazed bricks mostly in blue, with animals and deities in low relief at intervals, these also made up of bricks that are molded and colored differently. 
The gate, being part of the Walls of Babylon, was considered one of the original Seven Wonders of the World. It was replaced on that list by the Lighthouse of Alexandria from the third century BC.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_LIGHTHOUSE</zType>
		<en-US>The Lighthouse of Alexandria, sometimes called the Pharos of Alexandria, was a lighthouse built by the Ptolemaic Kingdom, during the reign of Ptolemy II Philadelphus (280–247 BC), which has been estimated to be at least 100 metres (330 ft) in overall height. 
One of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, for many centuries it was one of the tallest man-made structures in the world. 
The lighthouse was severely damaged by three earthquakes between AD 956 and 1323 and became an abandoned ruin. It was the third longest surviving ancient wonder (after the Mausoleum at Halicarnassus and the extant Great Pyramid of Giza), surviving in part until AD 1480, when the last of its remnant stones were used to build the Citadel of Qaitbay on the site.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_APADANA</zType>
		<en-US>The Apadana is a large hypostyle hall, best said the great audience hall and portico at Persepolis and the palace of Susa. The Persepolis Apadana belongs to the oldest building phase of the city of Persepolis, the first half of the 6th century BC, as part of the original design by Darius the Great. Its construction completed by Xerxes I. 
The Apadana was the largest building on the Terrace at Persepolis. It was most likely the main hall of the kings. The columns reached 20m high and had complex capitals in the shape of bulls or lions. 
The Apadana at Persepolis has a surface of 1000 square metres; its roof was supported by 72 columns, each 24 metres tall. The entire hall was destroyed in 331 BC by the army of Alexander the Great. Stones from the columns were used as building material for nearby settlements.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_MAUSOLEUM</zType>
		<en-US>The Mausoleum at Halicarnassus or Tomb of Mausolus was a tomb built between 353 and 350 BC in Halicarnassus (present Bodrum, Turkey) for Mausolus, a native Anatolian from Caria and a satrap in the Achaemenid Empire, and his sister-wife Artemisia II of Caria. 
The Mausoleum was approximately 45 m (148 ft) in height, and the four sides were adorned with sculptural reliefs, each created by one of four Greek sculptors: Leochares, Bryaxis, Scopas of Paros, and Timotheus. 
The finished structure of the mausoleum was considered to be such an aesthetic triumph that Antipater of Sidon identified it as one of his Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. It was destroyed by successive earthquakes from the 12th to the 15th century, the last surviving of the six destroyed wonders.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_ACROPOLIS</zType>
		<en-US>The Acropolis of Athens is an ancient citadel located on a rocky outcrop above the city of Athens and contains the remains of several ancient buildings of great architectural and historic significance, the most famous being the Parthenon. 
While there is evidence that the hill was inhabited as far back as the fourth millennium BC, it was Pericles (495–429 BC) in the fifth century BC who coordinated the construction of the site's most important present remains including the Parthenon, the Propylaea, the Erechtheion and the Temple of Athena Nike. 
The Parthenon and the other buildings were seriously damaged during the 1687 siege by the Venetians during the Morean War when gunpowder being stored in the Parthenon was hit by a cannonball and exploded.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_COLOSSUS</zType>
		<en-US>The Colossus of Rhodes was a statue of the Greek sun-god Helios, erected in the city of Rhodes, on the Greek island of the same name, by Chares of Lindos in 280 BC. One of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, it was constructed to celebrate its successful defense against Demetrius Poliorcetes, who had besieged it for a year with a large army and navy. 
According to most contemporary descriptions, the Colossus stood approximately 70 cubits, or 33 metres (108 feet) high, making it the tallest statue of the ancient world. 
It collapsed during the earthquake of 226 BC, although parts of it were preserved. In accordance with a certain oracle, the Rhodians did not build it again.>
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_MUSAEUM</zType>
		<en-US>The Musaeum at Alexandria, which included the famous Library of Alexandria, was an institution said to have been founded by Ptolemy I Soter. This original Musaeum ("Institution of the Muses") was the home of music or poetry, a philosophical school and library such as Plato's Academy, and also a storehouse of texts. 
It did not have a collection of works of art, rather it was an institution that brought together some of the best scholars of the Hellenistic world, analogous to a modern university. 
The Mouseion's scholars conducted scientific research, published, lectured, and collected as much literature as possible from the known world. In addition to Greek works, foreign texts were translated from Assyrian, Persian, Jewish, Indian languages, and other sources.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_CIRCUS_MAXIMUS</zType>
		<en-US>The Circus Maximus is an ancient Roman chariot-racing stadium and mass entertainment venue located in Rome, Italy. Situated in the valley between the Aventine and Palatine hills, it was the first and largest stadium in ancient Rome and its later Empire. 
It measured 621 m (2,037 ft) in length and 118 m (387 ft) in width and could accommodate over 150,000 spectators. In its fully developed form, it became the model for circuses throughout the Roman Empire. 
It was Rome's largest venue for ludi, public games connected to Roman religious festivals. Ludi were sponsored by leading Romans or the Roman state for the benefit of the Roman people and gods. 
Most were held at annual intervals on the Roman calendar. Others might be given to fulfill a religious vow, such as the games in celebration of a triumph.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_PANTHEON</zType>
		<en-US>The Pantheon is a former Roman temple, now a Catholic church, in Rome, Italy, on the site of an earlier temple commissioned by Marcus Agrippa during the reign of Augustus (27 BC – 14 AD). 
It was completed by the emperor Hadrian and probably dedicated about 126 AD. Its date of construction is uncertain, because Hadrian chose not to inscribe the new temple but rather to retain the inscription of Agrippa's older temple, which had burned down. 
Almost two thousand years after it was built, the Pantheon's dome is still the world's largest unreinforced concrete dome. The height to the oculus and the diameter of the interior circle are the same, 43 metres (142 ft). 
It is one of the best-preserved of all Ancient Roman buildings, in large part because it has been in continuous use throughout its history.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_HAGIA_SOPHIA</zType>
		<en-US>The Hagia Sophia is the former Greek Orthodox Christian patriarchal cathedral, later an Ottoman imperial mosque and now a museum in Istanbul, Turkey. It is famous for its large dome. 
Built in AD 537, during the reign of Justinian, it was the world's largest building and an engineering marvel of its time. It is considered the epitome of Byzantine architecture and is said to have "changed the history of architecture". 
From the date of its completion in 537 until 1453, it served as an Eastern Orthodox cathedral and the seat of the ecumenical patriarch of Constantinople, except between 1204 and 1261, when it was converted by the Fourth Crusaders to a Roman Catholic cathedral under the Latin Empire.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_EVENTSTORY_WONDER_VIA_RECTA_SOUK</zType>
		<en-US>The Ancient City of Damascus is the historic city centre of Damascus, Syria. The old city which is one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the world, contains numerous archaeological sites, including some historical churches and mosques.
Many cultures have left their mark, especially Hellenistic, Roman, Byzantine and Islamic. In 1979, the historical center of the city, surrounded by walls of Roman era, was declared a World Heritage Site by UNESCO.
</en-US>
	</Entry>
</Root>
